欢迎加入OCR小组 qq群906722936 字幕优先发布于群内
我们告诉自己我们是行尸走肉
Rick: We tell ourselves that we are the walking dead.
瑞克 我们还在一起
Rick We're in here together.
我们会失去一些人
Rick: We're gonna lose people.
甚至可能是彼此
Maybe even each other.
你可能会失去我
You can lose me.
不会
No.
如果我没能挺过去
If it's me who doesn't make it,
你就得带领其他人前进
you're gonna have to Iead the others forward
因为你可以
because you're the one who can.
瑞克
Rick!
为朱迪思创造一个未来
Making a future for Judith- -
这很值
it'll be worth it.
我们能做到的 我不会放弃
We can make it. I'm not giving up.
我这儿有东西
I have a B.
少将 我对调查腐败
Jadis: Major General, I'm taking great satisfaction
和背叛感到非常满意
in investigating corruption and betrayal.
我会解决的
I will fix it
我找到了属于勇者的东西
Michonne: I found something that belonged to the Brave Man.
什么意思
Judith: What do you mean?
妈妈
Mom
他还活着吗
is he alive?
我不知道
I I don't know.
但如果你觉得他还活着
But if you think he's alive,
那你就得去找他
then you have to go find him.
好 宝贝 我要去试试
Okay, baby girl. I'm gonna try.
去找他吧
Go get him.
我努力过
Rick: I tried.
请明白我努力过
Please know I tried.
入侵导致城市外墙倒塌
Male news anchor...the city's outer walls falling to incursion,
对抗措施失败
to countermeasures,
六小时内的街区陷落
to six- hour periods of neighborhoods falling,
最后整城沦陷
to the whole of the city.
有两个入侵点
There were two incursion points,
两处坍塌或者可能的引爆
two collapses or possible detonations,
大大阻碍了居民疏散
which effectively trapped the city's population.
似乎有一座
It appears that one building,
聚集了数百人的建筑
where hundreds of people gathered,
是最后覆灭的
was last to fall.
公民共和军的情报表明 尽管其大门没被丧尸攻下
And CRM intelligence states that, though its doors held,
但大楼内部发生了一些事情
something occurred inside the building itself,
引发了最初的几起死亡 病变复活 以及
leading to some initial deaths, reanimations, and the whole. ...
收割者格莱姆斯已被限制行动
Man: Consignee Grimes is tethered.
已就位
Inbound.
各位 公民共和国军队
Woman: Congsignees, the Civic Republic Military
感谢你们报名参加这次志愿任务
thanks you for signing up for this voluntary assignment.
这是一次三级危险事件
This is a level- three hazardous event.
阻止燃烧丧尸的推进
Eliminating the advance of ignited delts,
你们就能保护20多万人的庄稼
you are protecting crops and food stores
和粮食储备
for over 200, 000 people.
你们现在正在加快成为公民的步伐
You are now speeding up your path to citizenship.
基地 这是A队
Man#2: Base, this is Alpha.
所有收割者都已就位 准备执行
AlI consignees are in place and ready to execute.
收到 执行清理协议
Man#3: Copy. Execute clearing protocol.
上吧 收割者
Man#4: Go, consignees!
这边
Man: Over here!
这边还有一个
Man: Another one over here!
格莱姆斯 格莱姆斯
Man: Grimes. Grimes!
收割者格莱姆斯
Man: Consignee Grimesl
对不起 我在找我的斧头
Sorry. Trying to find my ax.
收割者格莱姆斯
Man: Consignee Grimes.
只能这样
This is how.
收割者格莱姆斯违反了协议
Man: Consignee Grimes is breaking protocol.
我看到他了
Man#2: I've got eyes on him!
收割者格莱姆斯 站住
Consignee Grimes, stop where you arel
收割者格莱姆斯
Consignee Grimes!
Rick: Aah!
你到底在哪儿
Man: Where the hell are you?
格莱姆斯 别动
Man: Grimes, freezel
只剩一个 只剩一个
Man: Down to one, down to one.
闭合包围圈 禁止射杀
Close circle. No kill.
米琼恩
Rick: Michonnel
瑞克
Michonne: Rick!
操
Oh, shit.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我的意思是
I mean.
你另有所指
You mean something else.
我不是本地人
Uh, I'm not from around here.
我迷路了 还迟到了
I'm lost, and I'm late for work.
你会不会
Do you know, uh
制图
cartography?
我不会
I don't.
我只知道怎么找地方
I just know where things are.
那是我该去的地方 但我不知道我现在在哪
Um, that'swhere I need to be, but I don't know where I am.
走那边
That way.
经过那座蓝色的大楼
Pass the big blue building.
然后就到了
You'll get there
我相信你
I believe in you.
你介不介意我
Do you mind if I just
我不介意
I don't mind.
我不是故意打扰你吃午饭的
I don't mean to interrupt your lunch.
你在这附近工作吗
You work around here?
是的
I do.
你喜欢吗
You like it?
算不上理想的工作
It's not where I want to be.
你现在的处境够理想吗
Are you where you wanna be?
我一直以为我会等到我们终于又在一起的时候
Rick: I always thought I would wait to tell you everything
再告诉你一切
when we were finally back together,
以为这只会是当我们老眼昏花
that it'd just be a story on the porch
太阳落山后在门廊上
after the sun went down,
随意说出的一个故事
when we could barely see each other,
但我现在必须告诉你
but I have to tell you now.
不是所有的
Not everything.
我无法面对一切
I can't face everything.
这是大部分 但所有的一切
This is most of it, but all of it,
都是为了回到你身边
it was always about getting back to you.
那桥上发生的事 我以为我死定了
What happened on the bridge, I didn't think I'd survive.
然后我在一家军队医院醒来
And I woke up in a military hospital.
一支军队找到了我 一支拥有数千人的军队
An army found me, a force of thousands,
保护着一座运行完善
protecting a working, hidden city
有数十万人口的隐秘城市
of hundreds of thousands.
安全和保密是最重要的
Security and secrecy above all.
那是军队的守则
That's the army's code.
所以谁也不能离开
So no one can leave ever.
这个城市实行自治
The city governs itself,
完全独立于军队
completely separate from the military.
但它遵循一个规则
But it follows that one rule,
一个来自墙外的法则
that Ilaw from outside the walls.
他们救下的人要在郊区工作
The people they rescue, they work in the outskirts,
杀死行尸以获取能源 或种植食物
killing walkers for energy or growing food
或管理水和废物
or managing the water, the waste.
六年之后 他们就能进入城市
After six years of it, they get into the city,
远离军队 远离郊区
away from the army, from the outskirts.
他们被称为收割者
They're called consignees.
我是他们中的一员 但我是永远不会进去的
And I was one of them, but I was never gonna go in.
我本想逃走的
I was gonna get away.
我本想回到你身边
I was gonna get back to you.
该死 我是真的想
God damn it, I was.
收到
Man: Uh, copy that...
该死
God damn it.
本来可以用另一只手的 对吧
Okafor: Could've used the other hand, huh?
我来这里是因为我和比尔少将谈过了
I came down here because I spoke with Major General Beale.
-说我的事儿吗  -对
About me? - Yeah.
你有个位高权重的朋友 很幸运
You are lucky you got a friend in high places.
你是我的朋友 对吧
You're my friend, huh?
瑞克 我为你游说了
Rick, I lobby the head of what is likely
可能是如今这个星球上最强大的
the most powerful military on the planet,
军队首领
on your behalf.
我可能是你有过的最好的朋友了
I am possibly the best friend you ever had.
你的额头怎么了
What happened to your forehead?
某个像你一样的人干的
Someone like you happened.
一个可能更适合我的项目的人
Someone who may be better for my program.
你觉得留在这里
You think that staying out here
能让你更方便逃脱是吧
gives you a better chance at getting away.
不可能
It doesn't.
这只会给你多增加一次送死的机会
It just gives you another chance to die.
你可能已经注意到了
You may have noticed,
我不想看到这种事发生
I don't want to see that happen.
我要继续工作了
I'm going back to work.
瑞克 你听到我说的话了吗
Rick, did you hear what I- -
你不用再来帮我了
You don't have to do this anymore.
我第次尝试的时候 军队不知道该拿我怎么办
First time I tried, the army didn't know what to do with me.
因为没有人想过逃跑 没有人想离开
Because no one tries to escape, No one wants to.
他们是要把我关进监狱吗 还是把我处死
Would they put me in jail? Kill me?
一个叫奥卡福的中校
A Lieutenant Colonel named Okafor,
他说服他们让我继续做收割者
he convinced them to keep me a consignee,
结果我一直逃跑
and I kept trying to escape
但我跑不掉
But I couldn't.
我没法回来找你
I couldn't get back to you.
我一直想跑
I kept trying to get away,
所以当我们出去外界做任务的时候 他们会把我拴起来
so they put me on a leash when we went out into the world.
我逃不掉
I couldn't get away.
我没法回来找你
I couldn't get back to you.
我被困住了
I was trapped.
奥卡福保护了我 因为他说他在我身上看到了一些东西
Okafor protected me because he said he saw something in me.
他想让我加入他的计划
He wanted me to join his program,
加入他们的军队
to join their army,
用我的生命为他们服务
to use my life for them.
他是这样说的
He put it this way.
我一直想告诉你
I keep on telling you.
对于像我们这样的人
For people like us
活人无处可逃
...there's no escape for the living.
我把制服放在你公寓了
I left a uniform in your apartment.
是时候接受事物本来的样子了
It's time to accept things for what they are.
上次害你丢了一只手
It cost your hand last time.
下次 就是你的命了
Next time, it's your life.
做点有意义的事儿吧
Do something with it.
我应该感谢你
I should thank you
而不是朝你扔东西
instead of throwing glasses at you.
为什么
Why?
你让我明白我是逃不掉的
You showed me I can't get away.
该死
Esteban: Shit, man,
我听说了 但是好家伙啊
I heard about it, but damn
你真的砍自己手了吗
You really did that shit for real, huh?
埃斯特班
Hey, Esteban.
我能摸一下吗
Can I touch it?
开玩笑的 朋友
Nah, just playing. Jokes, man.
好吧 大概有两年
Okay, so for like two years,
你都没跟我说过话
you didn't even talk to me.
也没跟任何人说过话
Or anybody.
但我一直在跟你说话
But I kept talking to you.
花了点时间 但我们现在终于有进步了
Took a while, but we got something now.
我们现在终于说上话了 所以
We got something, man, so
那个隐藏的城市啊
ThaPhdden city?
你看到的可能是恶魔岛
The only thing you probably see Iike, Alcatraz.
但对于我们这些收割者来说 我们看到的是美好生活
For us consignees, thougn, we see that good life, man.
他们有空调噢
You know, they got air conditioning, man.
空调
Air conditioning.
屁股缝再也不会发潮了
I mean, no more swamp ass.
你懂吧
You feel me?
瑞克 今天可是个大日子
I mean, look Rick it's a big day, man.
我跟你说这些是因为这是我在外围基础设施
I'm telling you this shit because this is my last day
工作的最后一天了
out here working utilities.
从明天起 我就会在那里面了
As of tomorrow Ijm gonna be in there.
3区水电副经理
Deputy Manager of Water and Power of Ward 3.
六年过去了 伙计 我的任务结束了
After six long years, man, my consignment is over.
我就要进城墙了 好家伙
I'm about to be inside the walls, bitch,
当公民了
a citizen,
-我应该送你个礼物的  -得了 瑞克
I shoulda got you a gift. Come on, Rick.
你能送我什么
What the hell you gonna get me?
苦瓜脸吗
A scowl?
谢谢
Thank you,
虽然不知道你这是干啥
for whatever the hell this is.
这就是人生呗 兄弟
Yeah, well, it's life, man.
至少这个叫奥卡福的家伙
Hey, at least this Okafor dude's
不会再逼你做士兵
gonna stop trying to make you
之类的了
into a soldier and shit.
真的吗
For real?
还来啊
Still?
即使在你的手
I mean, even after you.
服了 哥们 你还不如赶紧把字签了
Shit, man, you might as well sign up
让他别再烦你了
just to get him off your back,
然后等你出去找麻绳
you know, and then make your next move
找啥东西的时候再做下一步
when you're out there scavenging for twine for some shit.
不过有件事我还没告诉你
Hey, one thing I haven't told you, though.
我在那里面有个姑娘 哥们儿
I got a girl, man, on the inside.
她是个记者
She's a journalist.
嗯 她在做一个关于水资源管理的报道
Yeah, she was doing a story on, like, water management
从没在这儿见过你呢
Never seen you here before.
你也加入了
You joined.
是啊
I did.
是小米
...is millet.
这个国家不产小米
Isn't exactly millet country,
但如果我能找到合适的品种
but if I could find the right one,
会带来巨大的改变
Man: Again...it could change things.
遵命 长官
Sir, yes, sirl
这是你的选择吗
Is that your choice?
这是旧事物的结束
Is this the end of it
新事物的开始吗
and the start of something else?
是结束
It's the end.
也是开始
灬and the start.
欢迎加入公民共和军
Welcome to the CRM.
你不是要迟到了吗
Michonne: Ah, I thought you were late.
是迟了
Yep. I am.
我可不能迟
Uh, well, I can't be.
我每天都在这儿吃饭
I do eat here every day
这个时间吗
Around this time?
你有点太急不可耐了吧
You're pretty eager, aren't you?
或许你也是
Maybe you are, too
我可不是
I'm not.
能不能至少
Can I at least-
进
Comin'.
Coming.
出来吧 瑞克
Okafor: Come on, Rick.
要上课了
Class is in session.
这是个士兵吗
It was a soldier?
是啊
Yeah. He was.
我本打算等到开会时再说
I was gonna hold this in the briefing room,
但我们要讨论的内容
but for what we're going to talk about,
是件既危险 又不合时宜的事
that would be neither safe nor appropriate.
这是什么情况
What the hell is this?
你们两个已经训练一年之久了
Okafor: You both have been training for a year.
也都成为了士兵 但你们不会以为
You're both soldiers now, but you don't actually think
只需要做做士兵这么简单吧
all of this was about you two just becoming soldiers?
我们要把你们培养成为领导人
It's about you two becoming leaders.
我要让你们成为
I am gonna help you become
公民共和军内部的领袖之一
part of force command within the CRM.
我逃了四次
I tried to escape four times.
我手都没了
Mm- hmm. I did this.
我之前还试图杀你
I tried to kill you.
是的 但你们两位能够帮我
Yes, but the two of you can help me
从内部改变这一切
change things from the inside.
坐吧
Sit.
你们二位拥有着
You both possess something
我认为公民共和军做出改变
I believe the CRM needs
所需要的特质
to become what it needs to be.
为什么还要做出改变
Why does it need to be anything else?
这座城市自给自足 运转自如
The city lives, it runs itself,
公民共和军管理着外部世界
the CRM runs the world outside.
在这个破败的星球独自屹立着
Everything is working when nothing else is.
人们无法离开
People can't leave.
他们没有自由
They're not free.
没人真正自由
No one's free.
至少在这个星球没有 但我们至少还活着
Not in this world, but we're alive.
你还活着 你原本早就该死了
You are, and you're not supposed to be.
公民共和军将他们找到的人划分为A等和B等
The CRM designates people they find as A's and B's.
A等人强壮有力
A's have a strength.
会为自己的信仰付出生命
A's will die for what they believe in.
人们追随着A等人的脚步
People follow A's.
而我们在这世界上遇到的
The people we cross in the world,
一部分带回来的人 他们被划分为B等人
the few we bring in, they're classified as B's.
他们每天渴求的只有生存下去
Everyday people who are just trying to survive.
B等人进入城市
B's get in.
而A等人殒命在外 除了你们两个
A's are sent away and killed, except you two.
-为什么  -因为我
Why? Me.
公民共和军需要改变
The CRM needs to change.
公民共和军需要强势的领袖来改变现状
The CRM needs strong leaders to change them.
把自己变成怪物
Being the monster to...
以求打败怪物
fight the monsters- -
这样不是长久之计
that can't last.
所以我才需要你们两位
And this is why I need the two of you.
而其他的秘密 等到
AlI the other secrets, you'll receive
你们逐级晋升上去时自会知晓
when you move up the ranks,
你会收到梯队简报
and you'll receive the Echelon Briefing.
-逐级晋升  -梯队简报
Move up the ranks. The Echelon Briefing?
那时你们便能得知所有信息 一切问题的答案
That's when you get all the info, the whys,
九成军队成员 和所有城市居民
the things 90%of our force doesn't know about
都不知道的事情
and 100%of our city doesn't.
他们想要我们当他们的领袖吗
Do they want us to be leaders?
他们知道这事儿吗
Do they even know about this?
今晚在这里发生的事
Here? Tonight?
告诉我们关于A和B等人的划分 还有那些秘密简报
Telling us about A's and B's and secret briefings?
不 这是我个人的意见
No. This is just me.
我认为只有作为A等人的士兵
I believe that A's who become soldiers,
成为领袖 才有可能
become leaders are the only thing
彻底改变公民共和军
that could possibly change the CRM.
那么 如果我们俩
So, if we share with the higher- ups
把你的话告诉高层
that you're saying these things- Mnh- mnh.
格莱姆斯 别把我俩当成一伙的
Don't say"we, "Grimes.
如果我是你囗中的A等人
If I'm an"A, "
如果我只考虑我自己
if I think for myself,
你怎么觉得我会配合你做那些事呢
why do you even think I'm gonna go along with all of this?
因为我相信只要你们两个人
Because I believe if either one of you
有机会拯救世界 你们都会去做的
had a chance to save the world, you would.
你们一定会的
You'd have to.
那本书 打开吧
That book open it.
我们谈谈冷战
Let's talk about the Cold War.
他想要改变现状
He wanted to change things,
潜移默化的改变军队
change the army without them even knowing it.
他还希望我帮助他
And he wanted my help to do it.
我会配合他 但这不是我的战斗
I'd play along, but it wasn't my fight.
听着
Look here.
你显然和我的看法不同
You're obviously looking at this different than I am.
再让我提到你把我和你相提并论
I hear you throw this "we" shit around again,
我就把你给了解了
I'lI end you.
你就是
Were you the one?
把他脸弄伤的那位
The one who cut him up here?
我向他开了枪 只是打偏了
I shot at him, just missed.
现在看来我没有
Guess I didn't.
你也打算朝我开一枪吗 索恩
You gonna shoot me, too, Thorne?
我曾经是南非海军的一员
I was in the South African Navy.
在潜艇上服役
Served on submarines.
在潜艇上打过扑克
Used to play poker on the subs.
我玩的很好
I was good.
不 我玩的棒极了
No. I was great.
我想知道自己技术到底如何
I wanted to see how great.
拉斯维加斯举办了最顶级的赛事
They have the best tournaments in the world in Las Vegas.
我就去碰碰运气
So I went there to try my luck.
我下场前一张牌也没打出去
I didn't play a single hand before the lights went out,
所以我的运气坏的不能行
which tells me my luck is apparently shit.
他在大西洋发现了我
He found me in the Atlantic Ocean.
我那时已经濒临死亡
I was half dead.
我试着杀掉他以图留在那里
I tried to kill him so I could stay there.
我尝试了四次想要回去 那天是个开始
It was my fourth time trying to get back since the start.
也是结束
Or the end.
我知道你为什么要那么干
I know why you've done what you've done.
试着逃跑
Trying to escape.
把手砍下来
Taking your hand off.
和我的理由一样
Same reason I had.
外面你有你爱的人
There's someone you love out there.
我已经接受了
Yeah. I've accepted
我不会再见到我所爱的人
that I'm not gonna see my someone again,
因为我知道 那人不想要我死掉
because I know that person doesn't want me to die,
或许正是因此 我才只是
and that is probably why I just grazed
擦伤了奥卡福的脸
Okafor's face.
我心里知道 我不可能活着
Somewhere deep inside, I knew I wasn't making it back
回到开普敦了
to Capetown alive.
如果我朝你开枪 格莱姆斯
If I shoot at you, Grimes,
我不会打偏的
I won't miss.
也不会故意只是擦伤你
I won't graze you, either.
我不在乎你在玩什么把戏
Now, I don't give a shit about what game you're playing.
你也听到他说我们会怎样
You heard what he said should have happened to us.
我已是孑然一身了
This is all I have left.
其他的 从前的人生
The rest? The life before?
我就当是死了
It's all gone.
你也是孑然一身
This is all you have left, too.
你想要找回的那个人
The person you are trying to get back to- -
她没死
Hey, she's not gone.
他们都没死
They're not gone.
她没有 他们都没有
She isn't. They aren't.
可我们已经死了
We are.
如果你需要我的帮忙 说就是了
If you want my help, just ask.
走啊
Come on.
去喝两杯 免得我们开始自相残杀
Let's go have a drink before we kill each other.
早些时候 军队又发现了两座城市
Early on, the army had found two other cities,
波特兰和奥马哈
Portland and Omaha.
地方不大 构成也不复杂
Not as big, not as sophisticated,
也没有对外保密他们的存在
and not keeping themselves secret.
这三座城市结成了联盟
AlI three cities became an alliance,
不过他们却不知道第三座城市在哪里
even though two don't know where the third is.
世界比我们想象的要大得多 米琼恩
The world is so much bigger than we knew, Michonne,
美好的多 却也残酷的多
so much better, and so much worse.
一眼望去 只看到生命被死亡包围
Beale: Life surrounded by death, all in one view.
不是吗
Isn't that right?
比尔少将
Major General Beale.
是的 长官 说的没错
Yes, sir. It is.
坐吧 格莱姆斯
Have a seat, Grimes.
在我们与波特兰和奥马哈结成的三城联盟中
Another thing we have over Portland and Omaha
我们还有一个优势
in our alliance of three XXXXXXX
不同于他们 我们不费吹灰之力就能隐藏好自已
is, unlike them, we're fairly well hidden without much effort
我知道联邦政府对亚特兰大做了什么
I saw what federal forces did to Atlanta. XXXXXXX
一把火烧了个干净 长官
They used napalm, sir.
简直是魔鬼
Monsters.
比行尸还要恶劣
Worse than the delts.
不过这支军队
But this force- -
当时的宾夕法尼亚州国民警卫队
as the Pennsylvania National Guard at the time- -
我们阻止了他们
we stopped them.
怎么做到的
How, sir?
牺牲
Sacrifice
运气
Luck.
冷静
Calm.
还有奥卡福
And Okafor.
奥卡福吗 长官
Okafor, sir?
当时他随着空军一起到来
He was with their Air Force.
本该轰炸掉整座城市
He was supposed to bomb the city,
但他却炸死了在林肯金融球场的
but instead, he bombed 4, 000 Marines
4000名海军陆战队员
staging at Lincoln Financial Field.
他转变了立场
He switched sides.
我也是
Well, I did, too.
从某种角度来讲
In a way.
你和索恩原本不可能进入公民共和军的
Beale: You and Thorne never would have been allowed into the CRM.
甚至都不可能成为收割者
You wouldn't have even been let into consignment,
但奥克福说服了大家
but Okafor made a compelling argument.
问你个问题吧 格莱姆斯
Let me ask you a question, Grimes.
如果你不想的话 就不用回答
I don't expect you to answer, and you don't have to.
我就只想看着你的眼睛问一问
I'm just gonna ask it and look in your eyes.
好的 长官
Yes, sir.
奥克福是在计划什么别的事情吗
Is Okafor up to anything I should know about?
没有
No. No.
No.
很好 瑞克
Good, Rick.
你问我们是如何得胜 如何存活下来的
You asked me how we won, how we survived.
那你是如何存活下来的
How did you survive?
牺牲
Sacrifice.
你试着逃跑四次
You tried to escape four times.
为什么现在又加入军队
Why are you here?
你想要杀戮吗
Do you want to kill?
还是想要死亡
To die?
还是说这一切又只是为了逃跑
Or is all this just another attempt to escape?
请你看着我的眼睛 长官
Look in my eyes, sir.
你说呢
You tell me.
我只是想和你一起看看风景 格莱姆斯
I'm just gonna share the view with you for a while, Grimes.
一切都被包裹在巨大的谜团之中
Everything was about secrets.
军队不惜一切将这座城市藏匿起来
The army kept the city a secret at all costs.
对这座城市来说 军队所做的一切亦是个谜团
Everything the army did was secret to the city.
还有那些穿着血红色条纹的士兵
And then there were the soldiers
他们所做的 一切
with those blood- red stripes
也对整个军队保密
keeping what they did a secret to the whole force.
一个秘密接一个秘密
Secrets on secrets.
而我唯一在意的 是保护好我的秘密
And the only thing I cared about was holding on to mine.
我们近期的模型推算出一个关键点
Our latest modeling shows a tipping point.
清算即将来临
There's a reckoning coming...
就在不远的未来
...and it's coming soon.
或许你会问
Okafor: Maybe you're asking,
就不能躲开吗
Why can't you just turn away? "
有时候是一个人 有时是两个
Sometimes one person, sometimes two.
他们有能力 有责任
...they have the power, they have a responsibility
改变一切
to change everything.
你会看到
You'll see it
面对
face it
而且我知道
and I know.
你会做出正确的选择
you'll make the right choice.
在决定性时刻
In that defining moment,
你会做出正确的选择
you'll make the right choice.
靠
Esteban: Oh, shit.
瑞克·格莱姆斯
Rick Grimes
我去
Rick: Shit.
埃斯特班·加西亚
Esteban Garcia.
是3区水务副经理埃斯特班·加西亚吗
Wait, is it Ward 3 Deputy Water Manager Esteban Garcia?
嘿 嘿 现在我可是正经理了好吗
Hey, hey, it's Ward 3 Water Manager now, right?
嘿 你的收割者夹克呢
Hey, where's your consignment jacket?
而且今天不休假的话你怎么会来这的
And how the hell are you even here if it's not a furlough day?
天
Oh, shit.
你加入了公民共和军
You joined the CRM.
搞什么
What the fuck?
检修孔下面的隧道
The tunnel under this manhole- -
我需要你告诉我它通到哪
I need you to tell me where it goes.
兄弟 我现在是高级水利水电人员
Dude, I am senior level water and power now, okay?
-我不能  -我必须继续尝试
I can'tjust...I have to keep trying.
我不会放弃的
I won't stop.
我马上就可以做到了 我能回家了
I'm getting there. I'm getting home.
不然我就要死了 就是这样
Or I'm dying. That's it,
听着 瑞克 我知道你是自己人
Look, Rick, you know you're my guy, man,
但我什么都不能说
but I can't tell you shit, alright?
就算我告诉你了
Even if I did tell you shit
我告诉你的
...you know, the shit I would tell you
肯定也绝对不是
would definitely not be that...
这个隧道会带你到达正东
this tunnel would take you due east
大约一英里外的一个路囗
to a junction about a mile out,
如果你那里碰巧有个上了挂锁的栅栏
and if there happened to be a padlocked grate there,
我百分百不会告诉你
I 100%wouldn't tell you
挂锁的密码是4399
that the code to open it's 4- 3- 9- 9.
我想告诉你的另外一件事就是
And another thing I'd tell your ass is that
我懂你 明白吗
is that I get it, alright?
但你没必要为这去死
But you don't have to die, man.
所以你不许死 听见了吗
So don't fucking die, okay?
基地 这里是黑鹰3号
Man: Base, this is Black Hawk 3.
我们有关于真-克洛的情报
We have tally on Gen- Klor.
五分钟后着陆
Wheels down in five.
收到 黑鹰3号
Man#2: Copy, Black Hawk 3.
经过了多年的训练
After all the years of training
以及与奥卡福之间的沟通
and the talks with Okafor,
扮演好士兵
playing the good soldier,
-我终于有办法回到你身边了  -快快快
I found a way back to you. Go, go, go.
-是个外勤任务  -进入厂区
It was a faraway mission...Man: Breaching facility.
去一个废弃的化工厂收集资源
...a resource run to an abandoned chemical plant.
我找到一具行尸的尸体
I got a walker body,
砍下了它的手
cut off its hand.
留下了我的身份识别牌
...left it with my dog tags.
尸体会被焚烧
The corpse would burn.
活人无处可逃
"There's no escape for the living, "
所以我必须确保他们认为我死了
so I had to make sure they thought I was dead.
不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no!
该死
God damn it.
等等 快回来
Wait. Get back.
我都看到了
I saw the whole thing.
来 没事的
C'mon. It's okay.
收到 资源提取完成
Man: Copy. Resource extraction complete.
药片都装车了
Tablets are loaded.
上报情况
Call it in.
找到撤离者
Evacuee located.
是一个孩子
A child.
正在护送她去撤离点
Escorting her to extraction point.
-收到  -他杀了我妈妈
Copy. - He killed my mommy.
他是个好人
He's a good man,
我们来自一个好地方
and we're from a good place.
我们会一起回去
And we are all gonna go back there.
所有人
AlI of us.
我们不能留在这
We can't be out here.
你说过有需要可以请你帮助
You said to ask for help.
我现在就求你
I'm asking.
我这就是在帮你
I am helping you.
他会找到你
He would have found you
还有你要去投奔的人
and whoever you're running to.
他了解你 格莱姆斯
He knows about you, Grimes.
现在赶紧走吧
Now, c'mon.
醒醒
Wake up.
你忘记敬礼了 士兵
You forgot to salute, soldier.
你都了解我什么
What the hell do you know about me?
我一直在想死去的人
I think of the dead all the time.
她的名字 就在纸条的背后
Her name, back of the note,
你的消息放在了三号逃生区的瓶中
your message in a bottle from escape number three.
我去了拉特岛 发现了瓶了
I went to Rat Island and found the bottle.
手机上画的是她 对吗
That was her on the phones, right?
我也都看过了
Yeah, I looked through those, too.
不过那孩子 是你女儿吗
The child, though, was your daughter, right?
还特么还有谁知道
Who fucking knows?
米琼恩可不是个普通名字
Michonne is an unusual name.
外面没多少人
Not many people out there,
但如果你是在
but if you start the search
我们找到你的地方开始搜索的
around where we picked you up...
那这信息就有用了
...that's potent information.
所以你觉得杀了我能增加你成功的机会
So I suppose killing me helps your chances.
也许我不该告诉索恩
You know, maybe I shouldn't have told Thorne
我知道你的事 但她都告诉我了
I know things about you, but she tells me things.
他们会派我去找你
They would have sent me to find you,
收拾我的烂摊子
clean up my mess,
然后最后除掉你
and finally erase you.
你就是我的责任
You are my charge.
我必须杀死你还有米琼恩
I'm the one who'd have to kill you and Michonne
还有你要去找的其他人
and anyone else you ran to out there.
知道这个
Just knowing about this- -
我不在乎为什么你浑身是血
I don't care why you're covered in blood,
为什么炸弹会炸 为什么他们回不来了
why the bombs go out, and why they don't come back.
你当然在乎
Yes, you do.
这不是我的城市
This isn't my city.
这些也不是我的人
Those aren't my people.
每个人都是你的人 所有活着的人都是
Everyone are your people. Everyone alive.
这不是我的一切
This isn't everything!
你没资格替全世界做选择
You don't get to choose for the world!
你没资格替我做选择
You don't get to choose for me.
我没资格 你有
I don't. You did.
是你自己选的
You made the choice.
我老婆才是我的选择
My wife is my choice.
我女儿
My daughter,
我的生活是我的选择
my life is my choice.
你认为我经历了那么多
You think I went what I went through,
做了那么多事
did what I did
是为了让别人替我做选择吗
to let anyone choose anything for me?
你做了选择
You made the choice.
你为那个城市的那些人而活
You live for those people in that city
因为除了职责什么都没有
because you got nothing else but your duty.
百分比和收益率 狗屁A等和B等
Percentages and yields, A's and fucking B's.
一个一无所有的好士兵
Some goddamn good soldier with nothing!
我失去了一切
I lost everything!
我炸了亚特兰大 炸了洛杉矶
I bombed Atlanta and I bombed Los Angeles,
我本来也会炸了费城
and I was en route to do the same to Philadelphia!
埃斯特拉 一个叫埃斯特拉的海军陆战队员
Estelle a Marine named Estelle- -
她是我老婆 她不想进去除掉
that was my wife, and she didn't want to go in
我未能全部除掉的人
to"liquidate"all the people I didn't manage to liquidate.
瑞克 我们不想看到另一个城市毫无意义的灭亡
We didn't want to see, Rick, another city die for nothing!
我有权力我也有选择
And I had power and I had a choice.
我杀了我老婆
And I killed my wife
和其他4000人
...and 4, 000 other people.
而我们救了成千上万的
And we saved hundreds of thousands,
也许就因为她的选择而救了整个世界
maybe the whole world with her choice.
对你我也努力过 瑞克
I tried with you, Rick.
我努力过
I tried.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你为什么道歉
What are you apologizing for?
让我走吧
Just let me go.
不行
No.
那你开枪吧
Do it.
拜托
Please.
我不会开枪的
I won't.
他们还跟你在一起
They're still with you.
但你在这里战斗
But you fight here now.
你为他们而战
You fight for them.
你已经做出了选择
You already made the choice.
我会调你去跟索恩一起负责后勤
I'm moving you to Logistics with Thorne.
在接下来的12个月里
You're gonna help convert a college in the Cascades
你将帮忙将卡斯卡德的一所大学转变为前沿作战基地
to a forward operating base over the next 12 months,
为前线做好战斗准备
battle- ready for the Frontliners.
所有高层公民共和军的指挥官
All top CRM commanders will convene a summit there
一年后将在那里召开峰会 正式开放基地
in one year to open the base.
你和索恩将成为
You and Thorne will be project leads
转换团队的项目负责人
on the conversion team.
这是你加入的机会
This is you getting in.
是你通往更高层
This is the start of your path
权力之路的开始
to the higher echelons of power.
我不想要权力
I don't want power.
这就是问题所在了
That's the thing.
你已经拥有了权力
You already have it.
你得看看这个
You have to see this.
看
Look.
未能参加与波特兰和公民共和军
Male news anchor...missing a scheduled rendezvous
早定好的
between alliance partners Portland
联盟伙伴会面
and the Civic Republic,
比尔少将为此让公民共和军进行了侦查
Major General Beale initiated a CRM reconnaissance mission
为了确认奥马哈的情况
to ascertain the status of Omaha,
他们已得知我们现在只剩两城联盟了
and they have learned that we are now an alliance of two.
奥马哈市
The city of Omaha,
美洲大陆幸存的三个城市之一
one of the three surviving cities on the continent,
已经陷落 包括其中的9万人
has fallen, and with it, nearly 90, 000 souls.
初步调查显示
Initial survey shows a collapsed section
该市周边屏障有一段坍塌
of the city's perimeter barrier.
在接下来的几周里 公民共和军将调查坍塌情况
In the coming weeks, the CRM will investigate the collapse
以确定这是否是来自行尸群所造成的压力
to determine if this was pressure from a dead mass- -
他们早该想到的
They should have seen it coming.
奥马哈让人们知道他们在哪 然后他们就死了
Omaha let people know where they were, and they died.
怎么 你认为这是人为的吗
What, you think people did this?
我不知道是谁干的
I don't know who did this.
我知道公民共和军还活着 可奥马哈却变成了死城
I know the Civic Republic is alive and Omaha is dead.
我知道秘密是干什么用的
I know that secrets work.
我知道一定是这回事
I know this is the answer.
这里是建设未来的地方
This is the place that will create the future,
而波特兰需要听我们的
and Portland needs to follow our lead.
你救的那个女孩
That girl that you saved- -
你在检修孔附近杀的行尸
those delts you killed at the manhole,
是她的父母亲
that was her mother and father.
他们住在一个博物馆里
They had lived in a museum.
她和一群人一起打猎
Her group, they hunted
种蘑菇 建栅栏
and grew mushrooms, built fences.
那女孩说 然后有一天行尸就进去了
And then the girl said that, one say, the dead was inside,
大家都死了
and then everyone was dead.
除了她
Except her.
她藏在了一个大雕像里
She hid in this giant sculpture.
是个长着尖刺的大蚂蚱
Said it was a grasshopper with these sharp spines.
她爬到下面
She crawled under there,
那些行尸
and the delts.
她认识的那些人
...the people she knew,
他们为了去咬她把自己搞得四分五裂的
they tore themselves up trying to get to her.
她身上都是他们的血还有内脏器官
She wound up covered in their blood and their organs.
两天后 她觉得自己再也撑不住了
...and after two days, when she couldn't take it anymore,
她终于走了出来 准备等死
she finally stepped out to die.
他们没有袭击她
They didn't attack her,
但她什么都没有了
but she had nothing left
也没有地方可去
and nowhere to go.
所以她就四处走
So she just walked
尽量不发出声音 藏好自己
and tried not to make a noise so she could hide.
你和我还有那个女孩
You and me and that girl
我们都想去别的地方
...we all want to be somewhere else,
想和别人在一起
with someone else,
但我们却被困在了这里
but we got stuck in the right place.
没错
We did.
你早晚有一天会看明白的
And you are gonna see that someday.
我阻止了你 可我不觉得抱歉
I'm not sorry I stopped you.
我救了你一命
I'm not sorry I saved your life,
尽管你不想被救
even when you didn't want it to be saved.
你没有救我的命
You didn't save my life.
我救了
Yes, I did.
我不会失手的 格莱姆斯
I wouldn't have missed, Grimes.
至少这个世界上还多了个好人
At least there's one more good man in this world, hmm?
一个试图拯救这个世界的好人
One more good man to try and save the world.
不管他是不是想要这样
...whether he wants to or not.
城市的外墙
Male news anchor...the city's outer walls
在入侵下倒塌 对抗措施失败
falling to incursion, to countermeasures,
六小时内的街区陷落
to six- hour periods of neighborhoods falling,
最后整城沦陷
to the whole of the city.
全城有两处侵入点
There were two incursion points,
两处坍塌或者可能的引爆
two collapses or possible detonations
大大阻碍了居民疏散
which effectively trapped the city's population.
似乎有一座
It appears that one building,
聚集了数百人的建筑
where hundreds of people gathered,
是最后覆灭的
was last to fall.
公民共和军的情报表明 尽管其大门没被丧尸攻下
And CRM intelligence states that, though its doors held,
但大楼内部发生了一些事情
something occurred inside the building itself,
引发了最初的几起死亡 病变复活
leading to some initial deaths, reanimations,
和整个
and the whole.
我想过结束它
I thought about ending it,
把一切终止
just stopping it all.
但之后
But then-
之后会不会都是一场空
then it would just be nothing, wouldn't it?
整件事 都是徒劳
AlI of it, for nothing.
我做不到
I couldn't do it,
但我仍决定赴死
but I still decided to die.
我一直在给你写信
I've been writing you letters the whole time,
联络你 唤醒内心的情感
reaching out, to feel something,
写信只是想象你可以读到它们
writing just to imagine you could read them.
这是我最后一封
This is my last one,
最后一封你读不到的信
the last letter I write to you that you'll never see.
我爱你
I love you.
我不再看重死亡
I don't see the dead anymore
或我所失去的人
or the ones I lost
或者太阳 天空 水流
or the sun, the sky, or the water.
我不再记惦着你
I don't see you anymore.
我只关注眼前的一切
I just see what's ahead.
金属转件 枪油和鲜血
Metal rotors and gun oil and blood.
为拯救世界我必须做的和我能做的事
What I have to do, what I can do to help save the world,
即使你不知道我做过
even if you don't know I ever did that.
我很爱你
I love you so much.
我非常非常爱你
〔love you so, so much.
我努力过
I tried.
请明白我努力过
Please just know I tried.
我努力过
I tried.
但我失败了
but I failed.
这是很大胆的举动 但你说你信任我
This is a pretty bold move, but you said you believed in me.
所以 如果你想独占这张长椅
So, if you want this bench to yourself,
我也可以带着这 大盒披萨走过大蓝楼
I can take this large pizza past the big, blue building,
在我糟糕的工作时间
and eat it alone at my miserable desk
在我乱糟糟的工位上独自吃掉
at my miserable job.
我确实信任你
I do believe in you.
我也很喜欢披萨
...and I do like pizza.
但别再说你的苦了
But shut up about your misery.
没人逼着你在这
You're not stuck anywhere.
你说过 你不在你理想的地方
Well, you said you're not where you wanna be.
我不在
I'm not.
但我也没被困在这
But I'm not stuck, either.
只要我们愿意 就能征服整个世界
We can make this whole damn world ours if we want to.
如果有一天
What if I came here one day.
我带了五个披萨
with five pizzas?
和一枚婚戒过来呢
And a wedding ring?
我觉得你应该这么做
I think you should do that.
我觉得
I think
我相信你
I believe in you.
我觉得
Ithink, um
瑞克
Rickl
谢谢你带我们去海边
Thanks for taking us up the coast.
我喜欢你开飞机时的沉默
I like the way you fly.
很难说是不是有心事
Hard to tell if there's anything on your mind.
这些天你都不怎么说话 瑞克
You rarely say shit these days, Rick.
我一直在想儿时的一个晚上
I've been thinking about this night when I was a kid.
那时七岁
7 years old.
我非常渴
I was thirsty,
睡不着觉
couldn't sleep,
所以我去接水
so I went to get some water.
老房子 吱吱叫的地板
Old house, squeaky floorboards,
尽量不吵醒家里人
trying not to wake my family.
我在楼梯上
I was on the stairs
看到厨房里有光
and I saw a light in the kitchen.
橘色的光
It was orange.
是庄稼着火了
The crops were burning.
我特别害怕 僵在原地
I was so scared, I couldn't move.
之后 我爸爸来了
Then, my dad was there.
他看起来像头怪兽
He looked like a monster.
半边身体着了火
Half his body was burnt,
但他是来救我的
but he was there to get me out.
他说我不必害怕
He said I didn't need to be scared,
那只是着火
that it was just the burning,
火焰是为了下季的丰收
that the flames were protecting the plants
在保护植物
for the next harvest.
他说 这也许看起来像世界末日
He said, "It may look like the end of the world,
但这只是开始
but it's only just the beginning. "
他非常镇定
He was so certain,
非常沉稳
so steady,
然后他
and he.
让我冷静下来
It made me calm.
我相信他
I believed him.
他活下来了吗
Did he survive?
他没事
Yeah, he was okay.
后来都没事
And it was okay.
我们有了一座新谷仓
We got a new barn,
新房子
new house.
下一年 是有史以来最好的收成
Next year, the harvest was the best it ever was.
很多年过去 我爸爸去世后
Years later, after my dad died,
我母亲告诉我
my mother told me.
那不是闪电点着的
that it wasn't lightning.
是他放的火
That he lit the fire.
农场要倒闭
That the farm was gonna fail
是他挽救了它
...and what he did saved it.
他救了我们
He saved us.
这颠覆了我对他的印象
And it just rocked me.
我以为他是我认识的最诚实的人
I thought he was the most honest man I knew.
我母亲说他的行为是错的
My mother said what he did wasn't right.
她说那些伤疤和疼痛
She said that the scars and the pain,
提醒着他
it just reminded him.
他救了我们
...that he saved us.
我加入
I'm in.
今年过得还不错
It's been a good year.
我知道你适合这支军队 瑞克
I know you're the right thing for this force, Rick.
我知道你适合这个计划
I know you're the right thing for this plan.
没有A等B等
No more A's and B's.
没有奥马哈
No more Omahas,
我实话跟你说
You know, I'm gonna be perfectly honest.
我还是不知道这一切要怎么解决 所以
I still don't know how it's all gonna work out, so.
我再告诉你一个秘密
I'lI tell you one more secret.
当你到那会儿了
When you get to that point
对剑发誓
...swear on the sword.
别让它得逞
Don't let it take.
你会明白的
You'll know.
相信我 你会明白的
Trust me. You'll know.
我们被袭击了 执行三号协议
We're hit! Protocol three!
执行三号协议
Protocol threel
报告
Reportl
奥卡福阵亡
Okafor KIA!
副驾倒下
Right seat down!
防守西边
Defending west!
天 火力攻击
Oh, God. Taking firel
我们被火力攻击
We're taking firel
十英里 C-126以南十英里
10 miles 10 miles south ofC- 126, C- 126.
我们要坠机了
We're going down.
稳住 稳住 稳住
Brace, brace, bracel
准备交火
Prepare to engage.
咱们走
Let's go!
六号三点固定 从左出口开始
Force 6, 3 points. Start at left exit.
-各就各位  -收到
Hit your PRBs. Copy.
向防线开火 现在
Free fire to the line, now!
前进
Move!
我叫米琼恩
My name is Michonne.
多年前我失去了一个人
I lost someone years ago,
但我刚发现他还活着
but I just found out that he's alive.
我需要自己去寻求帮助
I need to ask for some help myself.
我们会带你去你要去的地方
We'll take you as far as you need.
散开
Scatter!
就这样
That's it.
没有其他原因 没有私人目的
No other reason, no agenda.
米琼恩
Michonne.
Michonnel
瑞克
Rick!
你好 我是斯科特·M·金普勒
Hello. I am Scott M. Gimple.
我是“存活之人”的执行制片人
I'm the executive producer
和节目统筹
and showrunner of "The Ones Who Live, "
这是本集剧集揭秘
and this is your episode insider.
一支军队找到我
An army found me,
一支千人的军队保护着一座
a force of thousands protecting a working
数十万人口的秘密城市
hidden city of hundreds of thousands.
在行尸走肉宇宙中
Throughout the shows in The Walking Dead universe,
我们从各个方面认识了共和军
we've seen aspects of the CRM, in small ways and in big ways.
我们希望可以讲一个更宏观的故事
Our ambition is to tell, hopefully, a bigger story
对我向斯科特和罗伯特·柯克曼提出的问题
and have some answers that I'd been sort of asking Scott
还有这么多年其他的疑问
and, you know, Robert Kirkman
作出回答
and all the rest of them for years.
关于这个故事的起源
There was definitely atpaper trail to the CRM
共和军对此肯定有记录
from, you know, the genesis of this show.
我们有“行尸之惧”的故事
We've had stories on"Fear the Walking Dead"
展现他们为了抹去自己存在的证据
that have shown the Iengths they'll go to
干了多小事
just to erase evidence about them,
共和军不让任何人离开
and the CRM doesn't let anyone leave.
大部分人不想走 所以这不算一个问题
Most people don't want to go, so it's not really an issue.
你看到的大概是恶魔岛
The only thing you probably see is like Alcatraz.
对于我们这些收割者 我们到的是美好生活
For us consignees, thougn we see that good life, man.
我们第一次看到瑞克 他在城外
When we first see Rick, he's outside the city.
他还不是一个市民
He's not yet a citizen.
他加入共和军
He's been in the consignment program
收割者项目已经好几年
with the CRM for years.
还没有一个社区如此强人
There hasn't been a community that's been fortified enough
来运作一整个治理体系
to survive a system of governance
这成功了并且很了不起
that works and is amazing.
除了瑞克 大家都很乐意去那
Everybody but Rick is thrilled to be there
但瑞克不需要这个 瑞克需要他的家人
But Rick doesn't need that. Rick needs his family.
瑞克需要米琼恩
Rick needs Michonne.
你的额头怎么了
What happened to your forehead?
某个像你一样的人干的
Someone like you happened.
共和军在他到之后很快发现了他的优势
The CRM found his strength very quickly after he landed,
还是奥卡福介绍的
and it was Okafor who intervened.
这是一个很奇怪的关系
It's a kind of odd relationship.
他救过瑞克很多次
He saves Rick s life countless times.
因为瑞克总想逃跑
Because Rick is trying to escape,
奥卡福把他拉了回来
Okafor pulls him back in.
通常 只要你尝试逃跑
And, usually, it's one time you try to escape,
共和军就不纳入他们了
they just got rid of them.
他们不会让像瑞克这种人进来的
They don't bring in people like Rick.
他们会避免一些有个性的人
They avoid that vulnerability
打破这个地方的秩序
of bringing in somebody strong and charismatic.
你也加入了
You join.
珀尔·索恩是在外界被找到的
Pearl Thorne is another survivor
另一位幸存者
that was found out in the world.
如果不是奥卡福发现了她
If Okafor hadn't been the one to find her,
她是不会被带回去的
she would've never been brought back.
我们想要有人能和瑞克针锋相对
We wanted somebody that could stand toe- to- toe with Rick.
他们对彼此有着很大敬意
They have this kind of extraordinary respect
以至于多年后 这种敬意渗入到家庭中
that, over the years, bleeds into family.
我觉得她在他身上看到了自己的身影
I think she sees herself reflected back in him.
她比他看得更开 比如
You know, she's a little bit more ahead, in terms of, like,
好吧 我理解
"Okay, I've understood that
我仍思念着挚爱
I can still miss the love of my life,
但那是过去了 要专注当下
but that was then, this is now.
我们要做这些事才能有所发展
This is what we have to do in order to move forward. "
但瑞克永远不会忘记他的所爱之人
And Rick never forgets that.
我知道你是这支军队的合适人选 瑞克
I know you're the right thing for this force, Rick.
我知道你是这个计划的合适人选
I know you're the right thing for this plan.
让米琼和瑞克重遇
To have Michonne and Rick breathing the same air again
是最让人激动的事情之一
is one of the most exciting things.
你对这幕有一定期望
You have an expectation of a scene
然后这一幕要被演出来
and then you have the scene that actually occurs.
好消息是 有指定的演员
And the great news is that, with certain actors,
你可以直接调动他们
you can just tune in to them.
我只需要看着她的眼睛
And I just have to sort of look into her eyes,
然后就自然而然了
and then off we go.
一些事 幸运地
And something, fortunately, happened
发生的如此真实
that was real and felt true.
安迪和我 我们喜欢在片场
Andy and I, you know, we love to get in that sandbox
将栩栩如生的角色呈现出来
and bring them to life.
所以开启我们即将拥有的
So that was really fun to ignite the epic love- story journey
史诗爱情之旅真的很有趣
that we were about to take.